## Artur Kondas

#### Contact

Personal Site: akondas.com
Email: work@akondas.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/arturkondas

## **Profile**

Senior Software Engineer with over five years of experience in software development, consulting and support services. Skilled in automation, tech leadership, agile methodologies, architecture and mentoring. Always full of ideas and unconventional approach to problems, but still being able to see all the options and judge accurately. Willing to learn and improve, but at the same time to teach and help others.

Site Reliability Engineering Guild co-founder, lead & evangelist. Go enthusiast, open source contributor and trainer. Experienced in DevOps and reliable CI/CD practices. Advocate for asynchronous teamwork and team morale over sticking to pre-fabricated templates. I believe in continuous improvement not only in code, always learning something new.

Avid fan of remote working and work based on trust, not on numbers. I get stuff done (to put it mildly).

Outside of work - music producer, guitarist, amateur bread maker and electronics afficionado. Also I wrote first ever **music** video in Golang.

## **Employment**

Barclays (via ECS Digital) / Go Software Engineer

October 2020 - September 2021

- Built a set of highly secure Go AWS lambdas utilising Amazon Lex & Connect functionality ensuring high availablity to 9.4 million customers.
- Lead developer and a Key member of a team that scaled up availability from 0 to up to 70k chat conversations per day in 2 weeks time.
- Fully integrated with **DynamoDB**, leveraging some of the automation provided by the database, configured with **AWS**Secrets Manager, deployed over **AWS** Service Catalog.
- Helped refactoring existing lambdas and services to decrease spending by 40% on AWS.
- Introduced **Sonarqube** across the Go stack to increase
- Designed packages to abstract the logic within the lambdas and expose a simple and well documented API.
- Designed the architecture for multiple stacks and maintained the releases within multiple projects.
- Helped onboarding multiple new joiners and trained them in using Go and AWS services.

#### ECS Digital / Go Software Engineer

July 2019 - Present

- Designed and built a microservices suite for data scrapping and analysis using Go, Python, PostgresDB and graph databases (dGraph, neo4j).
- Services were designed to work in tandem with AI-powered analysis suite.
- Reworked the POC written by a previous team to decrease the time of discovery from 12 hours to 10 minutes.
- Reworked the architecture from previous monolyth solution into a **fully orchestrated microservices suite** with multiple interfaces for various programming languages.
- Utilised the power of Goroutines to make the solution scalable and asynchronous.
- Introduced tiered logging to the service to increase observability.
- Leader of SRE Guild in the company.
- Mentor and upskill a lot of new joiners in the company.

#### Calipsa / Full Stack Software Engineer

January 2019 - July 2019

- Built and maintained a set of microservices for video data processing and AI integration.
- Using Google Cloud services, NodeJS and custom ffmpeg wrappers.
- Refactored the database queries to **increase speed** of retrieving the data.
- Improved the **code quality** and **readability** within the whole stack.
- Increased the **test coverage** across the whole stack by **50**%.

/ Scrum Master

March 2019 - July 2019

- Introduced **Scrum and Agile** workflow and mentality in the company.
- Made first steps in building asynchronous communication mindset across teams.

Sparta Global / Software Development Technical Trainer

September 2018 - January 2019

- Trained three cohorts of students working currently in UK Home Office, Three Mobile or UK Ministry of Justice.
- Taught web development, backend programming using Java, Ruby, Python and C#.
- Mentored and managed students to help them achieve their true potential.
- Recognized by the board for willigness and skill for tacking unexpected challenges.

ABB / Application Specialist

January 2018 - June 2018

- Designed a process & tooling system for validating web suite post-deployment. Decreased the time needed from 4 hours to 5 minutes.
- Application specialist working on **globally available** web suite presenting ABB tools, systems and parts.
- Managed wordpress, various CMS and SQL databases

/ IT Support Specialist

March 2017 - December 2017

- Harnessing the power of **ServiceNOW**, built a set of data boards visualising the state of service desk, **SLIs and KPIs** across different teams which resulted in massive **decrease of backlog** and **increased the speed of resolution**.
- Member of internal project audit that processed entire applications' move from Poland to India, including knowledge and staff training.

Capgemini / English Customer Service Advisor

August 2016 - February 2017

#### Skills

Programming Languages Go/Golang, Rust, Python, Javascript/NodeJS, C/C#/C++

Database PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, dGraph, Neo4J, AWS Suite (RDS, DynamoDB)

Frameworks/Libraries gRPC, GraphQL, ffmpeg

Infrastructure Terraform, Ansible, Chef

Cloud & Orchestration AWS, GCP, Kubernetes, RDS, EC2, S3, Docker

CI/CD Jenkins, Puppet, GitHub Actions

Version Control Git, GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket

Project/Team Management Agile, Scrum, ITIL

Automatic/Static Deployment tools GitHub Pages, Netlify, Heroku

#### Certfications

- Gremlin Chaos Engineering Practicioner Gremlin July 2021
- Certified Kubernetes Application Developer The Linux Foundation July 2021
- Site Reliability Engineering Foundation DevOps Institute May 2021
- AWS Certified Database Specialty Amazon March 2021
- Mulesoft Certified Developer Mulesoft January 2021
- AWS Certified Developer Associate Amazon October 2020
- ITIL Foundation Conlea June 2017

# Open Source / Volunteer

- Speaker Devops Playground
  - Delivered a live-streamed workshop on building a ready-to-deploy, CRUD API in Go. Link here.
- Speaker Golang in London
  - Delivered a live-streamed workshop on building small app to play music from the terminal. Link here.
  - Delivered a live-streamed presentation on how to structure small Go programs. Link here.
- Guest Speaker ColorInTech
  - Delivered two workshops on annual ColorInTech events .
- Contributor Chef
  - Contributed to 5.2.0 #95
- Contributor Grafana Labs
  - Contributed to 7.0.0 beta #22898
- Contributor Rod
  - Contributing to overall functionality of a Chrome Devtools driver in Go.
- Contributor / Translator GitHub
  - Translated Unshaky and Rectangle to Polish.
- Translator Microsoft
  - Contributed to VS Code translation to Polish.
- Technical Trainer Codebar
- Technical Trainer CodeFirst: Girls
  - Delivered two editions of CF:G.

### Education

Cracow University of Technology Power Engineering / BEng

2013 - 2017

Engineering thesis:  $Acoustic\ measurements\ of\ electrical\ engines$